well the overactive thoughts are
basically already a symptom of you being
overly well overly committed or overly
engaged or overly invested emotionally
in things so you can't necessarily
directly just go ahead on and stop your
thoughts because there will be also a
form of thinking which means you'll be
contradicting internally but what you
can do is basically see how they came to
be how did you end up in a place of your
mind spinning out of control and I think
always you will find out that because
you were not restrained beforehand do an
obvious training things who said things
you've done things you wanted to do and
now obviously the mind is still sort of
running on that momentum so the most you
can do in those in those cases is just
not add more to it don't do any things
by body speech or further by mind on
account of a restless spinning out of
control mind but endure it because it
will tire out and come down
but you try to learn from it in a sense
of this is an indication of the problem
it's not the problem in itself the
problem in itself is basically the fact
that you were acting under strain as in
you know you got into an argument you
said things out of heat
some like I don't know over engage in
sensuality and then you only committed
and you couldn't stop when you wanted to
now you're paying the consequent and
things didn't end up the way you wanted
to and so on and then yes then the mind
is just gonna be revolving like crazy
but because of your behavior you
wouldn't have had the ground normal
mental for such for such a while while
spinning if you didn't provide it for it
but if you just try to arm I stop
thinking and give me a mutation and he's
are stop thinking yet not change my
behavior because most of these things
when they pretend to mind they're more
of like symptoms or the underlying issue
of greed aversion delusion your will
last and so on they are not the problem
in themselves because people usually
think meditation or something will help
me like control my mind but underneath
that I'll still do whatever I want to do
whenever I want to do it however I want
to do it yeah yeah well basically you
want you want you want to believe that
removal of the symptoms removes the
underlined underlying illness
well that's that's fine that's fine in a
way of what fine to a degree but
obviously can become an issue when you
just can't commit to a choice when you
when you expect toys to be made for you
so you don't feel responsible and even
that again that is again a symptom of
you not accepting responsibility in the
first place because whatever you choose
even if even if it feels like that the
choice was placed upon you by
circumstances you choose to accept it
because you can say no to anything so if
you start thinking along those lines in
terms of that you can't avoid
responsibility no matter what you do
then it becomes different then you will
obviously think twice even in regard to
small decisions but then at the same
time you won't feel like it's the end of
the world in regard to big decisions
because responsibilities been brought
back on you so you can't you're not
ignoring it anymore and that's why
people get into that and decides to stay
because really what they're indecisive
about is whether they should take
responsibility or not but that's I mean
if you start reflecting upon it you see
that that's not an optional method you
are already responsible
well a better decision yeah he might not
end up the way you will hope to but you
won't be affected by that as much as you
would if you try to pretend that you are
not responsible in the first place
that's what people think like if they
refrain from choice they think they're
not choosing but the framing from choice
is your choice in regard to some other
particular choices which means it's
equally choice but if I don't commit to
this or that I avoid being sort of
burdened by those things but actually
you just you were just burned him by
non-committal which can be even worse
burning because it's much harder to see
oh yeah what forever I mean rather
speaking but yeah it's sort of it
establishes itself on the level of a
view so unless you unless you dig it up
yourself and sort of develop
transparency through it and see what it
is yeah you will maintain that view for
the rest of your life
and think you're rewarding
responsibility just in reality and
you're doing really making less well
making choices from a more inferior
perspective because once you accept
responsibility your perspective is much
bigger it's more unpleasant initially
but overall actually you have a greater
perspective on things and wait and what
they entail you know the responsibility
you're more like reactionary sort of
that and then just hope things will end
up well
I mean what Trudy got well maybe but
overall they don't because the worst
thing you can do is you know
responsibility for your own existence
so it's better off to accept
responsibility and then even if all of
your choices end up in failure or
whatever you have an achievement in you
hope for you still took responsibility
for it and that's that's that's a
greater achievement actually than any of
those particular achievements of your
choice